Peter Bertolette Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Peter Bertolette Papers.
undated, 1953-1990.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Bertolette, Peter.
4 linear feet.
Literary and editorial work of a former UConn student.
MSS19980197
Biography
Not available.
Scope and Content
The collection includes drafts and manuscripts of literary materials, correspondence, photographs and publications pertaining to Bertolette's literary and editorial/publishing career. The collection also contains materials concerning his tenure as a student including his years at the University of Connecticut.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of literary and University materials. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Irby, Kenneth, 1936- —Correspondence.; Metcalf, Paul C.—Correspondence.
Subjects:
University of Connecticut—Students.; American literature—20th century.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Personal Papers.; Notebooks.; Publications.; Photographs.; Financial Records.; Manuscripts.
Occupations:
Author.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Collection was donated by Bertolette and his heirs in 1983 and 1999.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Personal Materials, undated, 1953-1989
  - Art Museum publications, 1981-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Art work, 1988 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Childcare publications, 1971-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Childhood memorabilia, 1953 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Childhood memorabilia, 1953-1962 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Childhood memorabilia, 1962-1965 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Childhood memorabilia and school grades, 1962-1971 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Course, 1982 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Employment, 1978-1989 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Financial documents, 1968-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Financial documents, 1981-1989 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Franconia College catalogs, 1971-1973 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Journals, 1973-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Journals, 1977 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper course, undated (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Political interests, 1988 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
- Series II: Correspondence, undated, 1967-1982
  - Benson, Andrew, 1978 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Bertholf, Robert, 1977-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Blaisdell, Gus, 1977 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Boer, Charles, 1976-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - Buckeye, Robert, 1978 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - Butterick, George F., 1974-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
  - Byrd, Donald, 1977-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
  - Callahan, Bob, 1976-1977 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
  - Coolidge, Clark, ca.1976-1977 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - Gildzen, Alex, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - Ginsberg, Allen, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - Grener, Robert, 1974-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
  - Hogan, Ed, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
  - Irby, Kenneth, 1977-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
  - Laughlin, James, 1974 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
  - Lewis, Harry, 1978-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
  - McDonagh, Paul, 1977-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 33)
  - Metcalf, Paul, 1967-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 34)
  - Ortiz, Simon, ca. 1978 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
  - Plimpton, George, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 36)
  - Sigal, Clancy, 1977-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 37)
  - Skodnick, Roy, 1980 (Box 1:, Folder 38)
  - Sorrentino, Gilbert, 1978 (Box 1:, Folder 39)
  - UConn, undated (Box 1:, Folder 40)
  - Woolf, Douglas, 1977 (Box 1:, Folder 41)
- Series III: Notes and Writings, undated, 1971-1990
  - Calendar, 1983-1990 (Box 2:, Folder 42)
  - Franconia Priors, 1972 (Box 2:, Folder 43)
  - Franconia Priors, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 44)
  - Franconia Priors, 1974-1975 (Box 2:, Folder 45)
  - Notes
    - Class, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 46)
    - Class, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 47)
    - John Paul Jones, 1978 (Box 2:, Folder 48)
    - Journal, undated (Box 2:, Folder 49-50)
    - Journal, 1978 (Box 2:, Folder 51)
    - Journal, 1979-1980 (Box 2:, Folder 52)
    - Journal, 1980 (Box 2:, Folder 53)
    - Journal, 1989 (Box 2:, Folder 54)
    - Journal, undated (Box 2:, Folder 55)
    - UConn class, 1973-1974 (Box 2:, Folder 56)
    - UConn class, 1975 (Box 2:, Folder 57-58)
    - UConn class, 1976-1977 (Box 2:, Folder 59)
    - UConn independent study, 1975 (Box 2:, Folder 60)
    - UConn bound notes, undated (Box 2:, Folder 61)
    - UConn: Melville, Poe, Hawthorne, 1976 (Box 2:, Folder 62)
    - UConn: Olson, 1976 (Box 2:, Folder 63)
  - Olson related materials, undated (Box 2:, Folder 64)
  - Poetry, 1973 (Box 3:, Folder 65)
  - Poetry, 1982-1989 (Box 3:, Folder 66)
  - Poetry, 1989 (Box 3:, Folder 67)
  - Poetry, 1989 (Box 3:, Folder 68)
  - Poetry, 1989 (Box 3:, Folder 69)
  - “Bezoar”, 1978 (Box 3:, Folder 70)
  - Review
    - Buckeye, 1978 (Box 3:, Folder 71)
    - Metcalf, 1988-1989 (Box 3:, Folder 72)
  - Zukofsky, Burroughs, 1971-1972 (Box 3:, Folder 73)
  - Genealogical Research, 1989 (Box 3:, Folder 74)
  - Reference Material, 1989 (Box 3:, Folder 75)
- Series IV: Sarcophagus, 1976-1977
  - Typescript, 1976 (Box 3:, Folder 76)
  - Paste ups, 1976-1977 (Box 3:, Folder 77)
- Series V: Photographs and Tapes, undated, 1960-1983
  - Photographs, undated (Box 3:, Folder 78)
  - Photographs, 1960-1983 (Box 3:, Folder 79)
  - Photographs, 1989 (Box 3:, Folder 80)
  - Tape: Burroughs, undated (Box 3:, Folder 81)